David Craig Penner

Curriculum Vitae

4925 Dufferin Street Toronto, Ontario $M3H\ 5T6$ ⊠ david.craigpenner@mail.utoronto.ca www.davidcraigpenner.com in davidcraigpenner

My research is focused on investigating, and potentially improving, the properties of high-order generalized summation-by-parts operators and methods in the context of problems of increasing practical relevance, for example, fluid flow problems governed by the compressible Navier-Stokes equations.

Education

2016/9-present University of Toronto Institute for Aerospace Studies, Toronto, ON.

Ph.D., Aerospace Engineering, Sept 2021 (Expected)

Advisor: Professor David W. Zingg Direct transfer from M.A.Sc. to Ph.D.

2011/9–2016/5 University of Saskatchewan, Saskatoon, SK.

B.Sc., Mechanical Engineering, May 2016

Great Distinction

Experience

Research

2016/9-present Graduate Student Researcher, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON.

Project: Development and investigation of efficient high-order generalized summation-by-parts

operators for computational fluid dynamics

Advisor: Professor David W. Zingg

2014/5–2014/8 Undergraduate Student Researcher, University of Saskatchewan, Saskatoon, SK.

Project: Investigate the effect of Chromium on diamond deposition on ferrous substrates using microwave plasma chemical vapor deposition

Advisor: Professor Qiaoqin Yang

Industry

2015/5–2015/8 Student Field Engineer, PCL Construction, Regina, SK.

- Created a set of interactive, electronic construction drawings
- Supervised and directed subcontractors
- Received the highest student performance rating upon completion of work term

2013/5–2013/8 Engineering Technologist, Ground Engineering Consultants Ltd., Regina, SK.

- Conducted concrete sampling and concrete cylinder strength testing
- Performed foundation inspections
- Completed topographic surveys

2016/5–2016/8 Farm Hand, Schiller Organics, Regina, SK.

- Completed construction projects (carpentry and sheet metal)
- Operated and maintained heavy farm machinery
- Completed welding projects

David Craig Penner Curriculum Vitae

Scholarships, honours, and awards

2017	/9-2020/8	NSERC Alexander Graham Bell Doctoral Scholarship	$105000~\mathrm{CAD}$
	2018/7	International Summer School Scholarship, Beijing, China	$9000~\mathrm{CNY}$
2017	/9-2020/1	University of Toronto Fellowship	$34000~\mathrm{CAD}$
	2017/6	International HPC Summer School Scholarship, Boulder, Colorado	935 CAD
2016	/9-2017/8	NSERC Alexander Graham Bell Master's Scholarship	$17500~\mathrm{CAD}$
	2016/9	Mary H. Beatty Fellowships	5000 CAD
	2016/5	University of Saskatchewan M.Sc. Scholarship (Declined)	$17000~\mathrm{CAD}$
	2016/3	Most Innovative Mechanical Engineering 4 th Year Capstone Design Project	
	2016/3	3 rd place – Most Innovative 4 th Year Capstone Design Project	75 CAD
	2016/1	Nortek Air Solutions Canada Award	$2000~\mathrm{CAD}$
	2016/1	Douglas Durie Memorial Fund	$1000~\mathrm{CAD}$
	2016/1	University of Saskatchewan Scholarships	$3000~\mathrm{CAD}$
	2015/1	Douglas Durie Memorial Fund	$2000~\mathrm{CAD}$
	2015/1	W. R. (Buck) Staples Scholarship	2300 CAD
	2015/1	University of Saskatchewan Scholarships	$3000~\mathrm{CAD}$
2014	/5-2014/8	NSERC Undergraduate Student Research Award	5625 CAD
2012	/9-2016/5	Dean's Honour Roll in Engineering	
2012	/9-2013/4	David Dube and Heather Ryan Huskies Men's Football Award	$4300~\mathrm{CAD}$
2011	/9-2012/4	Huskie Football Foundation Awards	$4000~\mathrm{CAD}$

Journal publications (refereed)

- [2] D. A. Craig Penner and D. W. Zingg, "Superconvergent Functional Estimates from Tensor-Product Generalized Summation-by-Parts Discretizations in Curvilinear Coordinates," *Journal of Scientific Computing*, vol. 82, Feb. 2020. DOI: 10.1007/s10915-020-01147-7.
- [1] X. Sun, H. Ma, L. Yang, M. Sanchez-Pasten, D. Craig Penner, Y. Li, and Q. Yang, "Metal Dusting, Carburization and Diamond Deposition on Fe-Cr Alloys in CH4-H2 Plasma Atmospheres," *Corrosion Science*, vol. 98, pp. 619–625, Sep. 2015. DOI: 10.1016/j.corsci.2015.06.001.

Conference proceedings (refereed)

- [2] D. A. Craig Penner and D. W. Zingg, "Generalized Summation-by-Parts Methods: Coordinate Transformations, Quadrature Accuracy, and Functional Superconvergence," in *AIAA Aviation 2019 Forum*, Dallas, Texas: American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics, Jun. 2019. DOI: https://doi.org/10.2514/6.2019-2952.
- [1] D. A. Craig Penner and D. W. Zingg, "High-Order Artificial Dissipation Operators Possessing the Summation-by-Parts Property," in 2018 Fluid Dynamics Conference, Atlanta, Georgia: American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics, Jun. 2018. DOI: 10.2514/6.2018-4165.

David Craig Penner Curriculum Vitae

Presentations (excluding the above proceedings)

- [3] D. A. Craig Penner, A. L. Marchildon, K. J. Mattalo, S. Shadpey, and D. W. Zingg, "Novel High-Order Summation-by-Parts Methods for Computational Fluid Dynamics," Poster presentation, 1st Computational Science and Engineering Symposium, University of Toronto Institute for Aerospace Studies, Toronto, Ontario, Canada, May 2019.
- [2] D. A. Craig Penner, "High-Order Artificial Dissipation Operators Possessing the Summation-by-Parts Property," Oral presentation, 2018 International Graduate Summer School in Aeronautics and Astronautics, Beihang University, Beijing, China, Jul. 2018.
- [1] D. A. Craig Penner, "Development and Investigation of Efficient High-Order Generalized Summation-by-Parts Operators for Computational Fluid Dynamics," Oral presentation, 2017 International High-Performance Computing Summer School, University of Colorado Boulder, Boulder, Colorado, United States of America, Jun. 2017.

Teaching

- Fall 2017 Graduate Teaching Assistant, Fundamentals of Computational Fluid Dynamics
 - 2018 (AER 1316H), University of Toronto.
 - 2019 Instructor: Professor David W. Zingg Responsibilities: marking, guest lecturer

Mentoring

Assisted in the supervision of the following students

- 2018/5-2018/8 Alireza Razavi, Bachelor of Applied Science, University of Toronto.
 - Project: Applying optimized summation-by-parts operators to cut cell nodal distributions
- 2018/5–2018/8 Edward (Jun Tai) Luo, Bachelor of Applied Science, University of Toronto.

Project: Optimal boundary closures for high-order artificial dissipation operators satisfying the summation-by-parts property

Computer skills

underline denotes extensive use

Languages <u>Fortran</u>, <u>MATLAB</u>, Python, C++ <u>Environments <u>UNIX terminal</u>, <u>Windows</u> Software SolidWorks, ICEM CFD, Tecplot <u>Microsoft Excel</u>, Word, PowerPoint</u>

Professional memberships

2017/11-present Student Member, American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics (AIAA)

Other activities

2011/9–2013/8 **Athlete**, University of Saskatchewan Huskies Men's Football Team, Saskatoon, SK. Competed with the University of Saskatchewan Football Team for two years.